# Vijay Subramani

vijay.annamalai001@gmail.com | 9500373830

## **EDUCATION**

Chennai Institute of Technology
B Tech - Information Technology
2019 - 2023 | Chennai
CGPA: 8.89/10

**Sri Krishna Mat. Hr. Sec School** Higher Secondary (XII) Batch - 2019 Arakkonam Percentage : 70.67%

Vivekananda Vidyalaya Mat. Hr. Sec School

Batch - 2017 Arakkonam Percentage : 92%

## LINKS

#### GitHub:

https://github.com/Vijay-CIS

#### Linked In:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vijay-subramani-5b58371a3

#### **Portfolio:**

https://vijaysubramani.netlify.

#### INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

- Detail Oriented
- Good Communication
- Confidential
- Team worker
- Self Learner
- Adaptability

#### **HOBBIES**

- Photography
- Badminton

#### **SUMMARY**

Skilled multitask with superior work ethic and good team worker, problem-solving and organizational skills. Willing to take on any task to help team. Reliable and dedicated team player with hardworking and resourceful approach and detail-oriented with excellent observational, organizational and communication skills. To make use interpersonal skills to achieve goals of a company that focuses on customer demands and customer experience.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## HCL TECH | Java Full Stack Developer

Internship - Nov 2022 - July 2023 | Chennai

- Learnt Java concepts Java core, Oops, Java 8, SQL, JDBC, Maven, JSP & Servlet, Hibernate/JPA, Spring MVC, Spring boot, Spring security, JUnit 5, Swagger UI, SonarQube, Micro services.
- Agile Methodology that focus on the collaboration and efficiency to deliver quality products.

## TECHNOCIS | Front end UI/UX Developer

Internship - Feb 2021 - Nov 2021 | Arakkonam

- Collaborated with senior developers. Developed and maintained responsive front-end interfaces using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, ensuring seamless compatibility across multiple browsers and devices, resulting in improved user experience and customer satisfaction.
- Actively participated in daily stand-up meetings, providing progress updates and effectively communicating technical concepts to team members and stakeholders.

## **PROJECTS**

## **PET SHOP - Spring MVC**

- GitHub Link <a href="https://github.com/Vijay-CIS/Petshop-SpringSecurity">https://github.com/Vijay-CIS/Petshop-SpringSecurity</a>
- Developed a Pet shop application in Spring MVC where we can Create, Read, Update, Delete, Buy, Sell the Pet. It includes JSP, Validation, Java 8 features, Log4j2, Exception handling, Spring security, SonarQube reports.

#### **MOVIE APP - Spring RestAPI**

- GitHub Link <a href="https://github.com/Vijay-CIS/movieapp-api">https://github.com/Vijay-CIS/movieapp-api</a>
- Developed a REST API in Spring boot for Movie application. It includes CRUD operations, Validation, Java 8 features, Log4j2, Exception handling, Spring security, JUnit 5 testing, Swagger UI documentation, SonarQube reports.

#### **SKILLS**

- Java | OOPS | JDBC | JSP & Servlet | Apache Maven | Spring MVC |
   Hibernate | Spring Boot | Spring Data JPA | JUnit 5 Testing | Swagger
   UI | SonarQube | MySQL | MIcro Services | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap |
   Javascript
- IDE & Tools Eclipse IDE | VScode | Postman API Testing | MySQL Workbench | Adobe XD | Canva | GitHub | JIRA